Ewwww...
噁…
She ran away.
她跑走了
Unbelievable.
真是的
She is a hopeless shut-in.
她是無藥可救的家裡蹲公主
You saw for yourselves.
如你們所見
That was the princess of this nation.
我國的公主就是這副模樣
It won't be easy to earn the ring from her.
想從她手上得到戒指應該很難
Excuse me, but who are you?
請問您是哪位
I am Jade Lomka,
我叫傑德·洛姆加
the firstborn of the former King Lomka.
是前任風之洛姆加王的長子
The girl who ran away was the Ring Princess of Wind,
剛剛逃跑的風戒公主
Nephrites Lomka, my little sister.
涅芙麗緹絲·洛姆加的哥哥
So,
然後
are you the new Ring King people have been talking about?
你就是傳聞中的新任戒王嗎
What...
什…
What... What is the meaning of this?
你…你要做什麼
Release me! Let me go!
放開我 我叫你們放開我
We will keep him under our supervision for now.
他就暫時由我負責看管
Naturally,
當然
you will be treated as dignitaries.
我們也會把你們當作國賓禮遇
Satou...
佐藤…
Excuse me, did I do something wrong?
請問…我是做了什麼壞事嗎
My sister, Nephrites,
我妹妹…涅芙麗緹絲她啊
is a very sensitive person.
是非常纖細敏感的人
Well, she seemed a bit timid.
該怎麼說呢 感覺她有點膽小
She acted like a child...
精神上還很幼…
Your standards don't apply to her, cursed human!
別把自己的感覺套在她身上 臭人類
Listen closely. Nephrites is my angle.
聽好了 涅芙麗緹絲是天使
She is innocent and kind.
個性純真又善良
Despite her bashful demeanour,
雖然有一點內向
she likes her big brother a lot.
卻非常喜歡我這位兄長
She is such a nice little girl!
是一個非常非常乖的孩子
However,
不過呢
for various reasons, she has never set foot outside the palace,
因為某些原因 別說到國外了
much less another country.
她幾乎沒有離開過王宮
She is not accustomed to seeing outsiders.
因此不太習慣面對外人
Besides, she is only 54 years old.
而且她才54歲
It's way too early for her to get married.
現在就論及婚嫁還太早了
Fifty-four years old...
54…
As her older brother,
我身為兄長
I must stay by her side, nurturing and safeguarding her with my warmth.
應該陪在妹妹身邊 溫暖地守護她成長
You'll stay here for the moment.
你只要暫時乖乖待在這裡就好
We will release you in 80 years.
沒多久 只不過短短的80年
Eighty years?
8…
By then,
只要經過這段時間
Nephrites will be a bit more mature.
涅芙應該也會有所成長吧
She can wait all she wants,
等等 就算她無所謂
but I don't live that long!
我的壽命也…
Is this really appropriate?
做這樣的事真的沒關係嗎
It doesn't matter.
沒關係
The Abyss King or not,
管他是深淵王還是什麼的
our nation will be safe as long as we have the gust barrier.
這個國家只要有暴風屏障就很安全
Our top priority is to protect the source that powers this barrier,
保護這個力量的源頭風之戒
the Ring of Wind.
才是最重要的事
TALES OF WEDDING RINGS
《婚戒物語》
It's been three days.
已經三天了啊
Am I going to rot in here forever?
我該不會真的要永遠待在這裡吧
Ring King.
戒王
Who are you?
妳是誰
Keep your voice down.
不要大聲嚷嚷
What are you trying to achieve by collecting the five rings?
你收集五只戒指的目的是什麼
For world peace?
實現世界和平
For power beyond anything?
獲得無人能敵的力量
For the beautiful princesses?
還是得到美麗的公主們
I don't know what you want,
雖然不知道妳想做什麼
but I want to give Hime a happy life.
但我的希望是讓小姬幸福
I want to have a happy marriage with her!
和小姬過著幸福的婚姻生活
A weirdo indeed.
真是個怪咖
You have the power of the Ring King,
明明擁有戒王的強大力量
but you only set your eyes on one woman.
眼裡卻只有一個女人
I admire that.
我很欣賞你
Come with me.
跟我來吧
Why are you helping me?
妳為什麼要幫我
I am the person who safeguards the nation's future.
我是守護這個國家未來的人
Only you have the power
能和深淵王對抗的人
to stand against the Abyss King, Ring King.
戒王 只有你
Prince Jade locked you up despite knowing that.
明知道這點 傑德王子還是把你關起來
He did it to keep the barrier up.
一切都是為了那道暴風屏障
It's a cage that keeps our people here.
那是…把精靈關在這裡的牢籠
All right. Here we are.
好了 我們到了
This is the Shrine of Wind,
這裡就是風之神殿
where the Ring of Wind resides.
風之戒的所在地
The ring...
戒指?
Yes.
沒錯
That is one of the five rings,
那就是力量之戒的其中一只
known as the Seal of Wind.
風之玉璽
Nephrites was supposed to inherit that ring.
本來應該由涅芙麗緹絲繼承的東西
What is it doing here?
為什麼戒指會在那種地方
Shouldn't the princess carry it instead?
不是應該在那位公主手上嗎
Hide!
快躲起來
A giant fur ball is moving.
毛球在移動
No. That thing is...
不是啦 那是…
Father, Mother,
父皇 母后
the Ring King has come from the outside world.
戒王已經從外面的世界來到這裡
He is going to take me and the ring away.
他打算搶走我和戒指
But I will never let myself be taken to the outside world.
但我絕對不會到外面的世界去
I will do as you said, Mother.
我會遵從母后的吩咐
Please continue to defend the peace of this nation.
請你們繼續保護這個國家的安穩
Does she always pray to the statues?
她總是像那樣 對著父母的石像祈禱嗎
Statues? You are mistaken.
石像? 你誤會了
They are two pathetic guardians
那是心已經死去
whose hearts have died, and their bodies turned into stone,
身體化成石頭後 依然繼續使用戒指的魔力
but they continue to generate the barrier with the ring's power.
產生暴風屏障的可悲守護神
They are the former elven king and his queen.
前任的精靈王和皇后本尊
Who's there?
是誰在那裡
We've been made.
被發現了嗎
Chirp-chirp-chirp...
啾啾啾…
What are you doing?
你…你在幹嘛
Isn't it obvious? I'm trying to muddle through.
還用問嗎 當然是蒙混過去
You fool!
笨蛋
There are no birds in here!
這種地方怎麼可能會有鳥
Do... Do you want to play hide-and-seek?
想…想玩捉迷藏嗎
Sh... Show yourselves, intruders!
給…給我滾出來 可疑的傢伙
It's me, Ring King Satou.
是我 戒王佐藤
Ring... Ring King!
戒…戒王
Unbelievable.
真是的
She is still just as timid.
她還是一樣膽小呢
Your Highness, did something happen in there?
公主殿下 發生了什麼事
We wouldn't want anyone to find us here.
被王宮的人發現就麻煩了
Take Nephrites with us, Ring King.
帶著涅芙麗緹絲一起來吧 戒王
Where are we going?
要去哪裡
Relax.
別擔心
I know the lay of this place like the back of my hand.
我對這個地方瞭若指掌
You can count on this elven elder.
包在精靈長老身上吧
You... You're an elder?
長…長老
Your Highness?
公主殿下
Nephrites has gone missing?
涅芙麗緹絲不見了?
Yes.
是的
I saw her entering the Shrine of Wind.
我確實看到她進入風之神殿
But she went missing afterwards.
之後就失去蹤影了
Has anyone seen Nephrites?
有沒有人看到涅芙麗緹絲
Could it be...
難道說…
I've known her from the moment she was born.
我從她出生起就認識她了
She may be a shut-in,
雖然現在變成這副模樣
but she is resilient.
但她是很堅強的孩子
This shouldn't be too much for her.
適度的強硬手段 她應該能承受
Fulfil your mission. Earn her ring.
完成你的使命 取得她的戒指
Take your time.
你慢慢來
No, no, no!
不對不對
No!
不對…
I'm only after the ring.
我只是要取得戒指
That's all and nothing else.
沒有任何非分之想
Ring... Ring King!
戒…戒王
Calm down! I won't hurt you!
沒事的 我什麼都不會做
Please calm down!
妳冷靜一點
I knew it.
果然
There's no doubt about it.
肯定沒錯
It's that scoundrel's doing!
是那傢伙幹的好事
That's correct, Jade.
你說對了 傑德
Elder.
長老大人
The Ring King and the Ring Princess of Wind have left.
戒王和風戒公主一起離開這裡了
They eloped.
他們倆私奔了
E... Eloped!?
私…私奔
Impossible.
不可能
Nephrites is too scared of strangers.
那麼害怕外人的涅芙怎麼會…
High time you faced reality, Jade.
認清現實吧 傑德
Your little sister eloped with the guy she likes!
你妹妹和喜歡的男人私奔了
She will never say "I like you, Big Brother" ever again!
她再也不會對你說出 "我最喜歡皇兄"這種話了
Jade. You need to cool your head.
傑德 你稍微冷靜一下腦袋吧
It's the princess' destiny to inherit the Ring of Wind
公主的宿命是繼承風之戒
and become the Ring King's power.
成為戒王的力量
Your action is not in Nephrites' best interest.
你的行為不是在替涅芙麗緹絲著想
Nephrites' best interest...
替涅芙麗緹絲…著想
My parents still have the ring.
戒指現在仍然在父母他們手上
The nation is still protected by its power.
國家受到它的魔力保護
That's all that matters.
這樣就夠了
Nephrites doesn't need to inherit the ring.
涅芙麗緹絲不需要繼承戒指
Elder, I'm going to search your residence.
長老…我要搜查妳的住所
Sorry.
對不起
I'm sorry you had to wash my clothes too.
還讓你連我的衣服一起洗
I had to wash mine anyway.
反正我的衣服也得洗
I threw up on the legendary Ring King, who came from another world.
我竟然弄髒了 來自異次元的超常存在戒王
How could I do such a terrible thing?
我怎麼會做出如此可怕的事
Hey,
我問妳
am I really that scary?
我有那麼可怕嗎
You are very much so!
超可怕的
You didn't hesitate to answer that.
真是斬釘截鐵
I grew up inside the palace.
我一直在王宮裡長大
I've always been scared of outsiders.
所以很怕從王宮外面來的人
I was told you came from another country,
而且聽說戒王陛下是從國外…
a country that was not of this world.
從這個世界以外的世界來的
I did come from another world.
我的確是從另一個世界來的
But I'm not that special.
但也不是那麼特別的存在
The people in this world
跟這個世界的人
are pretty much no different from me.
應該也沒有太大的差別
What was your world like?
是怎樣的地方呢
I meant the world you lived in.
戒王陛下生活的世界
Well, let's see...
怎樣啊…我想想
Is it a scary place?
是不是很可怕的地方呢
With hordes of orcs and waves of goblins?
到處都是充滿半獸人和哥布林的海
Do dragons attack people on the street?
走在路上就會被龍襲擊
A world like that...
這樣的…
No! There are no monsters in my world!
不…我的世界才沒有那些魔物
You can even say it's pretty peaceful.
在這方面來說 算是很和平的…
What about elves?
精靈呢
Are there elves in your world?
戒王陛下的世界裡有精靈嗎
El... Elves?
精…精靈
Yes!
對
She's too close.
好近
I mean... There probably aren't any.
不 我想應該是沒有
I see.
這樣啊
Are you interested in my world?
難道妳對我生活的世界感興趣嗎
After all, I was told you were a shut-in.
因為我聽說妳是家裡蹲公主
I thought you'd hate this kind of thing.
還以為妳會更討厭這些事
Sorry! It was your brother who told me that.
抱歉 我是聽妳哥哥說的
Was I too rude?
這樣講是不是很失禮
It's all right.
沒關係
I know everyone says that about me.
我知道大家都這麼叫我
But I'm still interested in the world outside this palace.
而且我雖然對王宮外的世界有興趣
However, I am scared of learning the truth.
但會害怕也是事實
I read books about the outside world that I get from the Elder.
所以我平常會看長老大人給我的 關於外面世界的書籍
I imagine the view out there
想像外頭的景色
and the smells I'll find.
充滿什麼樣的味道
What is the world like?
是什麼樣的感覺
Simply thinking about it makes me excited and happy.
光是想像就讓人興奮又開心
I feel like I can go anywhere.
感覺哪裡都能去
But the truth is, I've been home the whole time.
實際上我卻窩在家裡
There is nothing I can do.
什麼都做不到
Weird, right?
很奇怪吧
There's nothing you can do...
什麼都做不到嗎…
We are very much alike.
我也跟妳差不多
I didn't come here because I possessed special powers.
我並不是因為有什麼特別的力量 才會在這裡
I only came here to be with the girl I like.
我只是不想和喜歡的人分開 才會來到這裡
Things may be tough, but as long as we try,
即使很難 只要勇於嘗試
we'll figure something out.
總會發現辦法解決的
As long as we try...
勇於嘗試…
I'd love to
總有一天 我想…
live in your world someday!
去看看戒王陛下生活的世界
Will you take me there?
你願意帶我去嗎
Take me there!
帶我一起去
I'm fine with that.
那倒是沒什麼問題
But before that...
前面…
Sorry! I was too caught up in the conversation!
對不起 我太專心講話了
But I don't get it.
我還是覺得很疑惑
You're so curious about the outside,
妳明明對外面的世界這麼感興趣
but why haven't you left the palace?
為什麼之前都沒有離開過王宮呢
That's because...
那是因為…
Nephrites!
涅芙麗緹絲
That voice...
這個聲音是…
Nephrites! I know you're in there!
涅芙麗緹絲 我知道妳在裡面
Come out!
快出來
I only became the Ring King because I wanted to be with Hime.
我是來追小姬才當上戒王的
It's my mission to collect the rings.
所以肩負著收集戒指的使命
However, I have no intention of forcing you into marrying me.
但我並不打算用這點逼妳和我結婚
Hime? Do you mean Princess Krystal?
小姬…是指克莉絲朵殿下吧
You can decide what to do with me.
我的處置就交給妳決定
I'll try my best.
我也會試著努力
I'm sure my brother will understand.
我想皇兄一定能理解的
Step away from her, Ring King.
離開她身邊 戒王
Satou...
佐藤…
Brother!
皇兄
The Ring King is not who you think he is.
戒王陛下並不是你想的那種人
Don't be silly.
說什麼傻話
He deceived you.
妳只是被他騙了
Our parents still have the ring.
戒指還在父母他們手上
The nation is still protected.
這個國家也因此受到保護
You know what's at stake.
這妳應該明白吧
That doesn't change the fact that I will inherit the ring someday!
即使如此 總有一天我還是得繼承那只戒指
I can't hide under your protection forever.
我不能一直躲在這層庇護之下
I must...
我必須…
Nephrites.
涅芙麗緹絲
I am not asking for your consent.
我並不是在問妳的意見
Are you going to betray our parents?
妳打算背叛父母的心意嗎
Come here.
過來我這邊
Princess Nephrites.
涅芙麗緹絲
Ring King,
好了 戒王
not only did you escape from your cell,
你不只逃獄
but you abducted our adored Princess Nephrites.
還誘拐我國的國寶涅芙麗緹絲
You should prepare for what's coming.
應該做好心理準備了吧
Hold on, Jade.
等一下 傑德
This is all my doing.
一切都是我安排的
Elder...
長老…
I have no idea what you're trying to achieve,
我不知道妳在想些什麼
but you've crossed the line this time.
但就算是妳 亂來也該有個限度
You're no better, Jade.
你還好意思說 傑德
The way you treated the Ring King was unforgivable.
你對待戒王的方式 也一樣不可饒恕
I will keep an eye on the Ring King.
戒王就交給我看管
I hope you don't mind.
你不介意吧
Very well.
好吧
You are not allowed to see Nephrites again.
你不准再出現在涅芙麗緹絲面前
Is that clear?
聽懂了沒
I was so worried about you.
我好擔心你
Are you hurt?
你應該沒有哪裡受傷吧
I'm all right.
我沒事
It wasn't easy to be locked up for three days, though.
雖然在牢房待三天很不好受
Wonderful. You were saved by the gorgeous princess.
太好了 有美女救你出來
And you two somehow became closer.
還在不知不覺間和公主變得很要好
Are you jealous?
妳該不會是在吃醋吧
What's wrong with that?
不行嗎
No, there's nothing wrong about it.
不 怎麼會不行
Sorry I couldn't visit sooner,
抱歉這麼晚才來打招呼
Ring Princess of Light.
光戒公主
I am the oldest elf in Lomka,
我是洛姆加最古老的精靈
Peridot.
佩莉多特
Erm...
那個…
I am the Princess of Nokanatika,
我是諾卡那堤卡公主
Krystal Novaty Nokanatika.
克莉絲朵·諾巴提·諾卡那堤卡
Elder,
長老…
did Nephrites become the way she is now
涅芙麗緹絲會那樣
because of her parents?
是不是與她的父母有關呢
Ring King, Ring Princess of Light,
戒王 還有光戒公主
I want you to know
我想讓你們知道
why Lomka is surrounded by a barrier of gust
為什麼洛姆加會被暴風屏障籠罩
and why Princess Nephrites became the way she is now.
為什麼涅芙麗緹絲會變成那樣
In the past,
原本…
Nephrites and Jade's mother
涅芙麗緹絲和傑德的母親
was not the first in line to inherit the ring.
並不是戒指的第一順位繼承人
She had an older sister.
她還有一位姊姊
To keep outsiders from having the ring,
為了不讓戒指外流
to keep the ring safe,
為了繼續守護戒指
there was a custom for elven princesses
從部落裡尋找入贅的女婿
to select a husband among our people.
是精靈公主的習俗
However, the older sister fell in love with a traveller.
可是大公主愛上一位旅行者
He was a human.
而且還是人類
The elves were sent into disarray.
精靈們開始恐慌
If the traveller could get one of the rings,
要是旅行者得到其中一只戒指
he could leave the tribe with it.
也許會把它帶出部落外
No. Truth be told, the traveller
不對 說穿了那位旅行者
approached the princess to get his hand on the ring.
根本是為了搶戒指才接近公主的
Rumours started spreading.
部落裡開始出現各種謠言
As rumours spread, people became paranoid.
謠言傳得越廣 就會變成懷疑
Paranoia eventually became a belief.
懷疑最終會變成確信
The stronger the objection,
周遭的人越反對
the deeper the princess' love for the traveller grew.
大公主對旅行者的愛意就越堅定
However...
但是…
The traveller left the princess.
這位旅行者 突然從大公主的眼前消失了
It's unknown whether our people banished him to protect the ring
不知道是被想保護戒指的精靈們 趕走了
or had him killed.
還是被殺掉了
That's terrible.
怎麼會…
People would go to such an extent for the ring?
有必要為了戒指做到這種地步嗎
The rings have always been a symbol of power since the mythical age.
力量之戒從神話時代開始 就象徵著權威的正當性
More exaggeratedly,
說得誇張一點
it serves as a symbolic declaration of the nation's justification for existence.
也是宣示國家存在理由的象徵品
For countries without those rings,
對沒有戒指的國家來說
they are so dazzling.
是很耀眼的東西
His disappearance was a relief for the elves.
當時部落的精靈們總算放心了
But to the princess
但是…
who had suddenly lost her lover,
看在突然失去愛人的大公主眼裡
who knew what they looked like?
不知道他們是什麼模樣
Warped by desperation and anguish, the grieving elder princess
因為絕望和憤怒 悲痛欲絕的大公主
left a curse
留下詛咒的話語
before leaving the nation.
就離開這個部落
"Let Lomka be consumed by the Abyss.
"讓洛姆加被深淵吞噬吧"
Let the inheritance of the ring be severed,"
"讓風戒公主斷絕傳承吧"
she said.
她這麼說
Curses are a heavy burden for elves
詛咒的話語對我們精靈來說很沉重
because of our longevity.
因為壽命很長
People lived in fear because they didn't know when she'd have her revenge.
必須永遠恐懼 不知何時會到來的復仇
As time went on,
隨著時間過去
fear slowly loomed over more and more people.
越來越多的居民被不安的念頭盤據
Even the royal family couldn't escape that fate.
連被留下來的王族們也是
Nephrites' parents inherited the rings in the elder princess' place.
代替大公主 繼承戒指的涅芙麗緹絲父母
Due to their fear for the curse,
害怕大公主的詛咒
they unleashed the Ring of Wind's power
為了不讓邪惡的東西接近洛姆加
to keep evil beings away from Lomka.
引出戒指的力量
A barrier of gust was cast around the borders.
在周圍設下風的結界
All of it was for the sake of this nation and their children.
一切都是為了保護國家和孩子
However, that came with a price.
但也付出很大的代價
Then, they made a deal with Nephrites.
然後他們與涅芙麗緹絲約好了
She was forbidden from leaving the barrier.
要她不准到暴風屏障外頭去
That was how the nation become caged.
這就是部落變成現在這樣的理由
Nephrites believes she must follow through or even risk her life
涅芙麗緹絲深信自己必須遵守 賭上性命保護這裡的父母說的話
Nephrites.
涅芙麗緹絲…
This is the last chance I can talk to you.
媽媽以後再也不能和妳說話了
An elf's lifespan has no limits,
雖然精靈沒有大限
but the body will be petrified
但只要心跳停止
when the heart stops.
身體就不能動了
Why did your heart stop?
為什麼母后的心跳會停止呢
Listen.
聽好了
You must never leave this nation.
妳絕對不能離開這個國家
Promise me.
這是約定
Until the day comes,
直到妳…之前
we'll keep protecting you.
我們都會守護妳的
Farewell, my beloved children.
永別了 心愛的孩子們
Mother...
母后…